Mob: 8107187335 | vikasrajoriaece11@gmail.com

Senior Project Coordinator cum Analyst with **4 years** of analysis experience in IT and Equity market. Proven track record of coordination and analyzing huge volume of data to gain business insights using python, Jupyter Notebook and Excel.

#### **Skills**

**Programming** Python, SQL, Excel, PHP, Basic Networking, TCP/IP and Web development

**Visualization** Excel Charts, Jupyter Notebook, Power BI

Tools MySQL, Outlook, Python, Python Profiler, Pandas, Numpy, Visual studio code

## **Certifications and Awards**

- IBM Python for Data Science and AI certification
- Completed Data Science certification course on LinkedIn
- Actively working in data science community at Jovian.ml platform.

# **Experience**

Aug 2019 - PRESENT

#### **MetLife GOSC, Jaipur** – *Project Coordinator*

- Assisting The Project Manager with the coordination of resources, meetings, and information.
- Responsible in handling the project from beginning to project delivery.
- Assigning the tasks to different teams as per scheduled time.
- Responsible to Maintain and monitor The IT Project with the goal of getting them on time.
- Tracking and motoring project activities and resources.
- Tasks includes Event handling and change Management.
- Managing a Master Data record and generating different reports from it.
- Prepared various Visualization in Excel and power BI for month on month business report.
- Evaluation and analysis of dataset using **Excel V-lookup and filters.**
- Worked closely with the engineering and business team.

Jan 2018 – July 2019

#### **GirnarSoft, Jaipur** – *Jr. Analyst*

- Closely worked with Data Team for ETL analysis on Data received from website and social media platforms, then putting all this data into centralized database called LMS.
- Extracting the data for tool to analyses then maintaining and publishing Data Reports.
- Understand the business using by received data, after that maintaining and publishing Data Reports.
- Coordinating with Teammates for the Data to analyze and present the same for improvement.

- These reports saved the time and helps in reaching out to new clients and offering them product as per their need.
- This helps in maintaining good relationship with existing clients as well as in making new customers.
- Ability to manage the multiple projects & clients.
- Having Mathematical skills to Estimate numerical data

Nov 2016 - Jan 2018

## **Professional Inffonet** – Market Research Analyst

- Worked with Data Management Team to Extract, Transform and load (ETL) analysis on Data received from different sources.
- Applying Technical analysis to understand the trends and patterns of stock to make right decision.
- This Analysis helps the team to invest at right time and gain more profit on selected stocks.
- Ability to fetch the Data from Index and doing screening and suggesting to client as per their budget.
- Ability to prepare portfolio for our stockholder after analyzing the performance of particular stock.
- Restructuring the portfolio to hold the winners and remove the looser from list.
- Help business to decide in dynamic pricing by identifying current data insights and forecasting the trends for future months using time series analysis using **Excel**
- Preparing a Dashboard for visualization after deeply analyzing each stock based on their past 10 year performance in market.

### Education

Sep 2011 - May 2015

NIT Yupia, Arunachal Pradesh - Bachelor in technology

7.79 CGPA